As part of the project for this lesson,
这节课的实战项目是
you'll write a CNN to classify dog breeds.
编写一个分类狗类品种的 CNN
The data set that we give you contains 8351 images,
我们提供的数据集包含 8351 张图片
each depicting a dog from one of 133 different breeds.
每个都是一种狗狗图片 共有 133 个不同品种
The goal is to create an algorithm that can predict breed just from a dog's picture.
目标是创建一种算法 可以根据狗狗照片预测品种
In this video, we'll show you how to use transfer learning for this task.
在此视频中 我们将演示如何使用迁移学习完成这一任务
We'll use the VGG-16 model pre-trained on the ImageNet data set.
我们将使用在 ImageNet 数据集上预先训练过的 VGG-16 模型
The dog data set is relatively small and it
这个狗类数据集相对较小
has significant overlap with a subset of the ImageNet categories.
与 ImageNet 类别的子集有很高的重叠性
We learn from the previous video that in this case,
我们从上个视频中了解到
we should slice off the end of the network and add
我们应该删掉网络的最后层级
a new classification layer with 133 nodes.
并添加一个新的分类层级 其中包含 133 个节点
We then train only the weights in this layer,
然后仅训练该层级中的权重
freezing all the weights in the other layers.
并冻结其他层级中的所有权重
There are many ways to accomplish this in Keras,
在 Keras 中可以通过多种方式实现这一目标
the most computationally efficient way will
计算效率最高的是
use the fact that the weights and the pre-trained network will never change.
利用权重和预先训练的网络始终不会改变这一事实
So we can take each image,
我们可以将每个图片
pass it through the network and stop at the last VGG-16 max pooling layer.
穿过该网络 并在最后的 VGG-16 最大池化层那停止
This turns each image into another 3D array,
这样会将每个图片变成另一个三维数组
which we can then save as part of a new dataset.
然后可以保存到新的数据集中
Then, when we go to code our network,
接着 当我们编写网络时
we'll use this new data set as input and our network in Keras will have two layers,
我们将使用这个新数据集作为输入 我们在 Keras 中的网络将有两个层级
an input and an output layer.
一个输入层和一个输出层
This new dataset is imported in line 3 of the notebook.
在 notebook 的第 3 行导入这个新数据集
We have passed each image through the network for you to save you some time.
我们已经让每个图片穿过该网络 以便为你节省一些时间
We will henceforth, refer to this new dataset as composed of bottleneck features.
因此我们将此新数据集称为由瓶颈特征组成的数据集
Going by what we learned in the previous video,
根据我们在上个视频中学到的知识
we need to create a model that takes a 7 by 7 by 512 array,
我们需要创建一个传入 7x7x512 数组的模型
flattens it to a vector and feeds it to a dense layer with a soft Max.
将其扁平化为向量并提供给具有 softMax 的密集层
That's what we've done here.
这就是这段代码的作用
We'll also summarize the model,
我们还将总结该模型
and we see that this model has more than 3 million parameters.
我们看到该模型具有超过 300 万的参数
It would take quite some time to train.
将需要很长的训练时间
We won't train it here,
这里我们不进行训练
but you're welcome to try it out on your own if you like.
但是如果你愿意的话 可以自己试试
We'll instead, do some dimensionality reduction through a global average pooling layer,
我们将通过全局平均池化层降低维度
which we'll also refer to as a gap layer.
全局平均池化层简称 GAP 层
We'll see that this greatly reduces the number of parameters that we'll need to train.
我们发现这样可以显著减少我们需要训练的参数数量
The previous model had over three million,
之前的模型具有超过 300 万个参数
but this one has under 70000.
但是这个模型的参数不到 70000
Next, we compile the model;
接着编译该模型
when we train the model,
当我们训练该模型时
it works lightning fast, even on CPU.
它的运行速度极快 甚至在 CPU 上也很快
This is because our model only has two layers.
这是因为我们的模型只有两个层级
If we didn't pre-compute the bottleneck features,
如果我们没有提前计算瓶颈特征
our training process would be much slower because we'd have to
那么我们的训练流程速度会慢很多
pass every image through a deep neural network at every epic.
因为我们需要在每个 epoch 中都让每个图片穿过深度神经网络
Next, we load the weights that got
接着 我们加载验证准确率最高的权重
the best validation accuracy and when we check the accuracy on the test set,
当我们检查测试集的准确率时
we see that we get around 46%.
发现结果大约是 46%
This doesn't sound too impressive until you consider that random guessing would
似乎不太理想 但是随机猜测的准确率
yield an accuracy of roughly 1 in 133 or less than 1%.
只有大概 1/133 或不到 1% 的准确率
But you'll have the opportunity to optimize further in the notebook.
但是你还可以在 notebook 中进一步优化
These gap layers haven't been around for long.
这些 GAP 层级的出现时间并不久
In fact, the first paper to propose
实际上 第一篇建议在 CNN 中
their use in CNNs was published a couple of years ago.
使用 GAP 层级的论文发表于几年前
Even more recently, in mid 2016,
甚至最近 在 2016 年中
researchers at MIT demonstrated that CNNs with gap layers
MIT 的研究人员演示指出
that have been trained for
经过分类任务训练并且具有 GAP 层级的 CNN
a classification task can also be used for object localization.
还可以用来进行对象定位
In other words, the CNNs not only tell us what object is contained in the image,
换句话说 这些 CNN 不仅能告诉我们图片中包含什么对象
they also tell us where the object is in the image.
而且可以告诉我们对象位于图片的哪个位置
If you'd like to try out some code that uses
如果你想尝试一些使用预先训练过的
a pre-trained ResNet-50 model to localize objects and images,
ResNet-50 模型来定位对象和图片的代码
please check out the links below.
请点击下方的链接
And that's all for now.
要介绍的就这么多
In the project, you'll have the opportunity to write your own CNNs from
在此项目中 除了训练利用迁移学习的模型之外
scratch in addition to training models that make use of transfer learning.
你还将有机会从头编写自己的 CNN
You're encouraged to try out as many architectures and ideas as you can.
建议你尝试尽可能多的架构和想法
Once you've trained your CNN to identify dog breeds,
一旦你训练识别狗类品种的 CNN 后
we'll guide you towards using your model in an end to end
我们将指导你在端到端算法管道中使用你的模型
algorithmic pipeline that could be incorporated into a fun online app.
并且可以将该模型应用到一个有趣的在线应用中
We can't wait to see what you create.
我们非常期待能够看到你所创建的模型